<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Self Hosting on Sean Lane</title>
    <link>https://sean.lane.sh/tags/self-hosting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Self Hosting on Sean Lane</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sean.lane.sh/tags/self-hosting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hosting a blog for free* in 15 minutes with Amazon AWS, Caddy Server, Docker Compose, and Ghost</title>
      <link>https://sean.lane.sh/posts/2018/08/Hosting-a-blog-for-free-in-15-minutes-with-Amazon-AWS-Caddy-Server-Docker-Compose-and-Ghost/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sean.lane.sh/posts/2018/08/Hosting-a-blog-for-free-in-15-minutes-with-Amazon-AWS-Caddy-Server-Docker-Compose-and-Ghost/</guid>
      <description>*Not including the domain name, of course. Also, this makes use of the portion Amazon AWS Free Tier that expires after 12 months, so only really free for that time. Should continue to be very inexpensive, though.
My wife previously utilized an online service to host a private journal, which has since been acquired. She wanted to switch to something else, and after scraping the new service which lacks a proper API or export functionality, we needed something else for her to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home backup strategy</title>
      <link>https://sean.lane.sh/posts/2018/07/Home-backup-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sean.lane.sh/posts/2018/07/Home-backup-strategy/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: CrashPlan died in May 2018, so I switched my family over to using Duplicati, restic, and rclone to sync backups both locally and in the cloud. As a bonus, we&amp;rsquo;re doing for free for the next year with Google Cloud Storage due to their 12 month, $300 free trial.
Motivation For the past two years or so from the date of this post, I&amp;rsquo;ve had my family using a piece of software known as CrashPlan for backing up all of the computers for my family, my siblings and their families, and my parents.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>