<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scripts on Sean Lane</title>
    <link>https://sean.lane.sh/tags/Scripts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scripts on Sean Lane</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sean.lane.sh/tags/Scripts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Extracting Entries from jrnl.com</title>
      <link>https://sean.lane.sh/posts/2018/08/Extracting-Entries-from-jrnl.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sean.lane.sh/posts/2018/08/Extracting-Entries-from-jrnl.com/</guid>
      <description>Relating to my previous post today about setting up a blog using AWS, Docker Compose, Caddy Server, and Ghost, I found the need to do some web scraping. A number of years ago, my wife began journaling her thoughts in an online service called LDSJournal.com (at least I believe that was the name). About 2 years ago, this service was acquired by a new site called jrnl.com. It seems to be a fairly neat service, but one thing we were concerned with is preserving the data should the account ever disappear.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Send a fax from the command line with Python and Phaxio</title>
      <link>https://sean.lane.sh/posts/2017/08/Send-a-fax-from-the-command-line-with-Python-and-Phaxio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sean.lane.sh/posts/2017/08/Send-a-fax-from-the-command-line-with-Python-and-Phaxio/</guid>
      <description>If you want to send a simple fax quickly, cheaply, and painlessly, Phaxio and Python make a nice combo. Below is a litte script that I wrote, based on this Ruby script by Pete Keen that is slightly out of date. There are Phaxios Python libraries, but I ran into a couple issues, and this seems to be the most brain-dead simple solution. Pros: No external dependencies. Cons: It uses the shell=True parameter for subprocess.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Filtering domain names on Domcomp.com with regex</title>
      <link>https://sean.lane.sh/posts/2017/02/Filtering-domain-names-on-Domcomp.com-with-regex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sean.lane.sh/posts/2017/02/Filtering-domain-names-on-Domcomp.com-with-regex/</guid>
      <description>Lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking around for another domain name that&amp;rsquo;s a little shorter and more flexible than seanlane.net. My purposes for that can be explained another time, but I have been trying to search domain names that have top-level domains (the .com part of google.com, for example) that are shorter in length, alongside some other attributes. There are a number of good tools to use for searching for available domain names, but I have not found any that allow for searching by the length of top-level domain.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
